Guide to the Jack Oliver papers, 1911-2004.
Oliver, Jack papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jack Oliver papers, 1911-2004.
16-14-3269
Jack. Oliver
18 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains a variety of documents and publications relating to Oliver's time at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Geologist, Irving Porter Church Professor Emeritus, Cornell University. Oliver was born in Massillon, Ohio, and went on to graduate from Columbia University in 1947, and then earn his master's degree and a PhD in Geophysics there. In 1968, after years of research, Oliver published a paper entitled "Seismology and the New Global Tectonics," that made a groundbreaking argument for the existence of continental drift, now known as plate tectonics. In 1958, while in a New York State seismic station, Oliver observed a seismic wave generated not by an earthquake, but by a nuclear bomb test in Nevada. Overnight he became an authority on the subject, which led to his being an adviser to the White House on the Nuclear Test Ban Treaty later than year, and a delegate to negotiations in Geneva in 1959. In 1971, Jack Oliver became the chair of the Department of Geological Sciences at Cornell University, and is known to have transformed the department from obscurity into a world-class facility. While there he and his colleague Sidney Kaufman co-founded the Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP), which has gone on to inspire deep seismic exploration programs in over 20 countries.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains a variety of documents and publications relating to Oliver's time at Cornell. The majority are miscellaneous papers and charts from various seismological events. There are some records of geology courses Oliver has taught in the past at Cornell as well as papers and slides from COCORP, Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling. The collection also contains papers documenting the wide variety of conferences and symposiums at which Oliver was in attendance. Multiple boxes house bound publications written by Oliver, including the drafts of his 1996 book, Shocks and Rocks, as well as his 1998 autobiography, Shakespeare Got It Wrong: It's Not "to Be", It's "to Do!"; the autobiographical memoirs of a lucky geophysicist." Also correspondence, lecture notes, committee minutes, and guide books (1911-1990). Additionally there are a number of papers from the Department of the Interior, and a “Certificate of Appreciation” from the Department of the Air Force.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Oliver, J. E. (Jack Ertle), 1923-2011.; Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (U.S.); Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Geology.
Subjects:
Geology--Study and teaching.; Geologists.; Seismology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Various Publications by Jack Oliver (Box 1)
- Charleston, S.C. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Iceland (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Micro-earthquakes (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Geologic Guide to Fairbanks, Alaska, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Penrose Conference (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Columbia College Today", 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Technology Review and Letter (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Richter Comments on Seis. and NGT and Reply (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Article for the Conservationist (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Ottawa - Symposium on Recent Crustal Movements (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Fenix and Seisson - re. Facility at Aiken, S.C. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- J. oliver - Du Pont (Box 2, Folder 12)
- SUNY, Binghamton, 3/11/75 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Unfiled Seismographs (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Publication, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Alphabetical Listings
  - African Seismic (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - AEC (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Agadir (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Arctic Ice Ridges - Alaska (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bullen (Inner Core) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chilean Earthquake, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Curvature - Effect on Surface Waves and Body Waves (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Computing - Watson Labs (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Core Velocity Meter (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Phase Velocity of Rayleigh Waves in the NY-PA Region (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Crustal Structure in the NY-PA Region (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Crustal Structure of the NY-PA Area (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sispersion Curves - Short per Ocean (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Diffracted Waves (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Diffraction of PKP (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Effect of Surficial Sediments on Continual Surface Waves (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Galapagos Project (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hardeman County, Texas (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Honolulu - SP Waves (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Love Waves, June 3, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Higher Modes of Continental Rayleigh Waves (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - ICE. Velocity Measuments (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lawrence, Kansas (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Leaking Modes and the PL Wave - Solio Comps (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Leaking Modes and the PL Wave - Ocean Calculations (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Leaking Modes and the PL Wave - Fairview Peak Records (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Leaking Modes and the PL Wave - Oral Paper (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - P Wave Dispersion (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Leaky Modes (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Leaking Modes and PL Waves - Theoretical Equations (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - LG Misc. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - LG Kiruna (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - LP Microseisms (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - LP Micros, June 6-7, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Long Period Seismic Waves From Nuclear Explosions in Various Environments (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Lunar Seismographs (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Microseisms (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Microseisms (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Additional Evidence Related to "A Worldwide Storm of Microseisms..." (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - A Worldwide Storm of Microseisms with Periods of about 27 Seconds (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Current Storms of Long and Ultra Long Period Microseisms (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Long Period Microseisms (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Microscope (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Love Waves - Low Velocity Layer (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Love Waves - Calculation and Curves (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Magnitude Calculation (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Micro-earthquakes in Nevada (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Figures for Micro-earthquakes in Nevada (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Computation Notebook (Box 3)
  - Computation Notebook (Box 3)
  - Model - Flexural Waves in a Plate (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cylindrical Rod (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mossbauer Effect (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 2nd M2 Paper (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Nagamune (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Noise with Periods Greater than 10 Seconds (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Normal Modes of Cont. Surf. Waves - Oliver and Ewing (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rayleigh and M2, June 3, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Baffin Bay, May 2, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Normal Modes of Cont. Surface Waves (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Nunn-Bush Well, Milwaukee (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - On the LP Character of S Waves (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - On the Long Period Character of Shear Waves (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Oceanic Crust (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Ocean Bottom Noise (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ocean Wave Recorder (Science File) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "On the Nature of Oceanic Seismic Surface Waves..." (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PcP, September 13, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PL Waves (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Propagation of PL Waves Across U.S. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Shear Coupled PL From Russian Nuclear Explosion (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - PPoS - Earthquake (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Phase Shift in Rayleigh Waves (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Phase Velocity of Rayleigh Waves (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Draft of Science Article on Reflection Profiling (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Higher Made Rayleigh Wave and Mystery Phase (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Rayleigh Waves at a Corner (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "Rayleigh Wave Dispersion in the Pacific Ocean..." (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Air-coupled Rayleigh Waves (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Reflection and Transmission Data (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Reflection and Refraction Coefficients - Knott (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Santiago (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - The Sea - Exploration of Sub-Oceanic Structure (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Sea-floor Spreading and Deep Eqs. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - The Second Shear Mode of Continental Rayleigh Waves (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Second Shear Mode - Oklahoma Shock, April 9, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Short Period Oceanic Surface Waves of the Rayleigh and First Shear Modes (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Second Shear Mode of Continental Rayleigh Waves (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Surface Waves - Absorption (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Surface Waves - Graphs of Theoretical Curves (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Surface Waves - AEC (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Surface Waves at Palisades from Nevada and Marshalls (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Surface Wave Studies - Earthquakes and Explosions, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Strain Meter (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Oklahoma - Hudson Bay to Palisades (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Seismographs (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Seismographs, October 6th, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Seismographs, October 10-19, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Seismographs, October 22-23, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Seismographs, October 30, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "The Seismic Noise of the Earth's Surface" - Brune, Nafe, Oliver (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Benioff Seismographs (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Shear Velocities in Oceanic Crust (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Sonic Boom Experiments (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - A Summary of Observed Surface Wave Dispersion (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Calibration of New L.P. Horizontal Seismographs (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Surface Waves - Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Surface Wave - Graphs Theoretical (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Summaries (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - AEC - Blanca and Logan (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Dispersion Curves for Russian Shots as Recorded at Agra and Hong Kong (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Seismographs for the Detection of L.P. Waves (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Notes (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Jim's Shock (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Oklahoma Earthquake, April 9, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - LQ/LR - George's Study (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Geneva Seismographs, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Telluric Currents (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - "Thirlaway's Method" (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Theor Comps - Dorman (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - T-Phase (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tsunamis (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Velocities, Rock (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Wichita Mountains - Seismological Observatory (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wichita Mountains - Seismological Observatory (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Well Seismograph Paper (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Files
  - Unlabeled Seismographs (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - COCORP Site Selection (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Background - Press Briefing (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - COCORP Site Selection Data (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Geneva - Press Releases, Newspaper Clippings, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Geology 687 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Geology III (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Geology 687, Fall 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - U.S. - Republic of China - Co-op Science Program (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Taiwan Conference - Taipei, May 28 to June 2, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Co-op Science Program - Correspondences and Photos (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Leather Conference Folder (Box 4)
  - WWSSN Fate (Box 4, Folder 19)
- U.S. - Japan: Earthquake Prediction Conference - 1964, 1968, 1973
  - "U.S. - Japan Conference on Premonitory Phenomenon...", October to November 1968 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Brochures, Maps, and Photos, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Data, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Publications and Papers, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Publications and Papers, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - General Conference Info, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - U.S.- Japan Conference on Earthquake Prediction, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Papers, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Proposed Conference on Earthquake Prediction - U.S.- Japan Co-op Science Program (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 3rd U.S.- Japan Conference (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Other Conferences and Meetings
  - Material on IUGG Symposium - Hamburg, Germany, August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - IGC - Paris, March 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - USNC/IUGG - Washington D.C., May 1979 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Coordinating Committee (I.C.L), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - INSPEI/IUGG Meeting - Canberra, Australia, December 1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Coordinating Committee Meeting, General Assembly- Hamburg, Germany, August 1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Coordinating Committee Meeting - Leeds, U.K., August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Cornell Papers
  - Jo's Engineering Freshman Advisees - Misc. Paperwork (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Ona Lacy (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Council Alumni Board Meeting, March 1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Cornell Council (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Faculty Council - Engineering College Council (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jo's Lecture for 107 and 108, Fall 1978 and Spring 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Geol. 621 and 631 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 694 Seminar (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Seminars on Recent Crustal Movements (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Geology 388 - Geophysics and Geotectonics (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Geol. 433 Final Exam (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Geol. 689 - Academic Year, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 12. Jack Oliver (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 16 - Page 233 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Course 383 - Continental Drift - Figures 15.1a thru 15-19 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Chapters 19, 20, and 21 Figures - Understanding the Earth (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 106 Questions (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - E106 Exams rtc. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Eng. 106 - Minicourse - Oliver #7 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rhodes Article 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Petroleum Lab, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - E-106 Petroleum Lab, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - E-106 - Well Logging + Petroleum Expl. Lab, spring 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Geology of the Cayuga Lake Basin" (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Minicourse, Spring 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Minicourse - E-106 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - E-106 Finals and Grades (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - E-106 Minicourse - Cycle 1 - Final Exams, Spring 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - E-106 Essays, Spring 1981 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - E-106, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - E-106 Questions (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - University of Leeds - Continental Extension Tectonics, April 1985 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Montana - Land - Baker (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Eng. Placements GPAs (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Computer Graphics Facility (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Proposition for Establishment of Program on History of Science - A + S (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Oliver, Jack - Oral Papers and Abstracts (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Misc. Papers and Handouts (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Article for "The Sciences" NYAs (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Alphabetical Folders containing Papers and Publications
  - Alberta (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Appalachians (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Authigenic Minerals and Diagenisis (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Coal (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Deep Source Gas Project and Gold (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Deltas (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dolomitization (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fluid Inclusions and Fluids (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General Petroleum, HC (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Geochemistry (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hydrology and Fluid Flow (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Hydrology and Fluid Flow (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Middle East (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Migration, Distillation (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Migration, Distillation (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mineral Deposits, Including Glauconite (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mineral Deposits, Including Glauconite (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Paleomagnetism (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Paleomagnetism (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Gerry Salisbury (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Thrusting, Loading, Etc. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Venezuela (+ Ref for Urals) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Wyoming (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Data
  - Earthquakes and Plate Tectonics (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Molto (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dig (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subcommittee on Energy Research, July 16, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Article for COMPASS - Blinders and Opportunity (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Geology" Cover Page, January 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Transparencies (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fluid References (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Evolving Continents (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 3-D (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Juan de Fuca - Cross Section Photos (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - NAS Paper and GSA Talk (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Exploration of the Continental Crust" Oral Presentation, July 16, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Paper for Science (Withdrawn) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - J.O. Note on "Publication of Science" (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Figures for Science (Withdrawn) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Exploring the Deep Crust of the Continents" (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - JGR Paper (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Seismic Charts (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Hearing, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Continental Tectonics and the Continental Lithosphere" (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Fluids Paper in Geology - Comment and Reply (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Fluids Expelled Tectonically..." (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Squeegee Hypothesis Talk (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Fluids Paper - J. Oliver (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Fluids Paper - Responses (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Fluids Paper - Rough Figures (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - J. Oliver (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Brewer et al. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Nature: News and Views (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Citation Classics (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - American Scientist Paper (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Scientific American Paper (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Paper for China (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - IGC Paper (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nature Article (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hardeman County - Apec (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - CRC Handbook of Physical Properties of Rocks (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Some Aspects of Continental Tectonics - AGU Talk, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jo - MS - International Symposium (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jo - MS- Figures for International Symposium (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "A Global Perspective on Seismic Relfection Profiling..." (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Geology 2020 - For Engineering Quarterly (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Geology 2020 - Department Lecture, December 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - VPI - Commencement Talk, June 9, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Geology Education Papers (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Geology Education (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - COCORP and the Continental Crust (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Jo's Drawings for Book (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Dean Everhart Memos (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - President Rhodes Memos (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Provost Kennedy (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 5 Year Plan (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Department - New Directions (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - WWII Paper (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Norman Haskell (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Seismology - Responsibilities and Requirements..." (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Strategy for Exploration of the Buried Continental Crust (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "The Incomplete Guide to the Art of Discovery", 1989 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Directions in Solid Earth Science During the 21st Century (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Illustrations (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Spots and Stains Figures (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Spots and Stains Paper (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Texas A + M - Geodynamics Symposium, April 1987 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Science Article (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Probing the Structure of the Deep Continental Crust - Science Paper (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Leonardo da Vinci Lecture, Fall 1980 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Seismology Lecture (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Seismic Surface-Wave Lecture (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jack Oliver - Popular Talks (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Columbia Engineering Quarterly (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Paper Drafts and Notes (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Paper Drafts and Notes, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Paper Drafts and Notes (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - LDGO National Conference on Drilling, May 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Deep Drilling - Industry Contacts (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Scientific American with J. Oliver Article (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Deep Drilling (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photos - Publicity (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Geology 621, Spring 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Papers and Publications (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Postglacial Uplift Lit. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Department of the Air Force Certificate of Appreciation (Box 9)
  - Topographic Map Index (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - East Canadian Faulting (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Nova Scotia - Misc. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nova Scotia Maps (Box 10, Folder 4)
- China
  - China (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Memo of Understanding Between Cornell and China (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - F. Press Ltr. rec. SRP in China (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - These Folders Turned out to be Empty (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Tibet (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - China Visit (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Chong Li Min (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Extra Copies of Oliver/Opdyke Draft (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - China (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Geology - China (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Jo - Visit to China, November to December 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Chinese Visit (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Travel - China (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Chinese Visitors to Cornell (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - AGU Talk - Final Version - Trends for the 1980s (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Other Areas
  - Republic of Congo (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Eastern Seismicity (Paper) (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - U.S. National Committee of Tunnelling Tech. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "World Data Center A", June 1971 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - NAS Committee on Seismology - Pasodena, February 1971 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - California Institute of Technology (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - SST - Sonic boom (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "San Francisco Earthquakes of 1957" (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - San Andreas Fault (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - San Fernando Earthquake (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Puerto Rican Seismicity (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Microearthquakes (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Reservoir Load-in Lit. (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Koyna Earthquake, December 11, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- The Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP)
  - COCORP Newsletters (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - COCORP Communities, Newsletters, etc. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - COCORP News Item (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Figures - COCORP (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Transparencies (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Figures - CDGO Compared to COCORP (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Kaudman (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Transparencies (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - COCORP Background and Papers (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - COCORP Misc. Papers (Bound Folder) (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - COCORP Misc. Papers (Bound Folder) (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - COCORP - Hardeman County, Texas (Bound Folder) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - COCORP - Various Unsorted Slides, Deep Reflection Profiling, Vienna, Early History of Plate Tectonics (Box 12)
  - Illinois, 1 (Box 13)
  - Illinois, 2 (Box 13)
  - Rhine Graben - IUGG Field Trip, 1967; 3 (Box 13)
  - Alps - IUGG Field Trip, 1967; 4 (Box 13)
  - Alaska Earthquake (With Caption Sheet), 1964; 5 (Box 13)
  - Post-glacial Faulting, 1965; 6 (Box 13)
  - Tibet, 7 (Box 13)
  - Mt St. Helen's (With Caption Sheet), 8 (Box 13)
  - Full and Partial Earth Set (With Caption Sheet), 9 (Box 13)
  - San Fernando Earthquake, February 1971; 10 (Box 13)
  - "Seismic Expression of Pre-Teritiary Structures In East and South Texas", 11 (Box 13)
  - Juan de Feca Plate to Alberta Plains (Transect B2), 12 (Box 13)
  - Untitled, 13 (Box 13)
  - Hazards, 14 (Box 13)
  - Jack Oliver, 15 (Box 13)
  - Untitled, 16 (Box 13)
  - Geologists Slice the Deep Basement, 1983; 17 (Box 13)
  - Northwest Cordillera Transect (With Caption Sheet), 18 (Box 13)
  - COCORP Slide Show Sound Track, tr-8781A (Box 13)
  - "New Sources of Energy" - Film, Audio (TR-8782A), and Description, 19 (Box 13)
  - "The San Andreas Fault" - Film, Audio (TR-8783A), and Description, 20 (Box 13)
  - Hawaiian Volcanoes - Slides (Box 13, Folder 1)